Yogyakarta, Indonesia rchmdaprks@gmail.com

Rachmadi Adji Prakoso

https://prxcmon.github.io +62 888 0271 9896

Experienced in the application-based IT security industry for more than two years. Such assessment methodologies, from scoping the target assets, then initiating the security testing, to delivering security issues along with its mitigations are the crucial steps to build the security mindset and implement it into the current working activity.

Work Experience

In-Contract Penetration Tester

Cyberkarta

July 2024 - Ongoing

Penetration Testing Team

(Onsite) Yogyakarta, Indonesia

Cyberkarta is one of the emerging security consultant companies in Yogyakarta, that provides IT security services and premium academy classes.

- Conducting and managing technical security assessment for high-profile clients, including application penetration testing (API, Android, and web application) and digital forensics.
- Building collaborative engagement with the team of clients' developers to build comprehensive security testing assessment, along with delivering assessment reports and providing security best practices.
- In-charge for leading in a team of Junior Penetration Testers to engage security assessments, ensuring the knowledge transfer and collaborative assessment can be addressed successfully.
- Engaged in a research and development of security assessment tools using templates from Nuclei as the references to advance penetration testing process.

Product Security Engineer

Xendit

May 2022 - February 2024

ISS Security Team

(Hybrid) Jakarta, Indonesia

Xendit is one of Indonesia's fastest-growing, tech-powered startup companies that provides financial services, including payment gateway services.

- Regularly secured Xendit-owned applications and products through expanding broader penetration testing (VAPT) scopes, including application programming interfaces (APIs), infrastructures and web applications.
- Initiated to engage wireless penetration testing assessment in order to enhance security measures of the office wireless networks.
- Continuously engaged in collaborative penetration testing with the developer team to ensure the security issues or vulnerabilities can be addressed before the security breaches or incidents arise.
- Engaged with the third-party IT security platform and the external security researchers to triage bug bounty reports and maintain communications of elaborating its severity findings and best practices.
- Conducted vulnerability assessments in accordance with PCI-DSS and ISO 27001 to ensure the implementation of the application security meets with the security standards and compliances.

Product Security Engineer Intern

Xendit

February 2022 - May 2022

ISS Security Team

(Remote) Jakarta, Indonesia

- Conducted several extensive research, such as Dynamic Application Security Testing (DAST) and Mobile Application Penetration Testing (MAPT), specified in Android environment to assist the product security team to perform related tasks.
- Started application penetration testing assessment under supervision to secure several scopes of Xendit-owned applications and products, including APIs and web applications, ensuring the testing progress is accurate.

- Started in a collaborative penetration testing engagement, from scoping targets, security testing, brainstorming of findings found, and finally remediation to deliver the implementation of security best practices.
- Developed comprehensive security test reports to address security findings and vulnerabilities to both security teams and product development teams.

Education and Certifications

B.E. Electrical Engineering, Universitas Gadjah Mada, Indonesia – GPA 3.22/4.00

2017-2021

• Certified Ethical Hacker, EC-Council, United States

2024

 $\underline{https://aspen.eccouncil.org/VerifyBadge?type=certification\&a=tQElESQyYapLQfAGVofD9HOnBD5V/ceblk1nQwKZIZk=}$

 Offensive Security Certified Professional, OffSec, United States https://www.credential.net/e7050ed1-562f-416e-8426-40430aa5d864 2024

Technical Skills

• Scripting : Bash/UNIX, C++, YAML

• Technologies : Aircrack-Ng, Android Studio, Apidog, Burp Suite, Docker, Drozer, GitHub, Kismet, Nessus, Nmap,

Nuclei, OWASP ZAP, Postman, Qualys

Latest Projects

 HackTheBox, Over 30 machines solved – Rank: Script Kiddie https://app.hackthebox.com/users/369370

Roadmap.sh, Self-learning projects of C++ and Data Structures and Algorithms
http://roadmap.sh/u/prxcmon